KSENIIA ZHYKINA WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT DETAILS

• Dresden, Germany

+49 1523 719 3901

zhykinak@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/kseniia-zhykina/

github.com/Zhikiki

Web Developer Portfolio: https://portfolio.zhikiki.dev

Open to RelocatingOpen to remote roles

SUMMARY

Web developer with background in strategic marketing and media-advertising. Experienced in negotiations and communication with different types of clients, working across multiply teams to translate business requirements into technology solutions, visions into executable projects with clarity and purpose.

SKILLSET

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- React, Redux, Angular, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS, JQuery
- Responsive Design
- Test- and Behaviour driven development (unit, integration, acceptance, end-to-end testing
- Native app development (React Native, Expo, PWA)
- UX/UI (user flow, user stories, user scenarios)

BACK-END DEVELOPMENT

- Node.js & Express
- APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google, Heroku, Netlify, GitHub pages
- PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firestore

ALSO PROFICIENTT IN

- GIT
- Chrome Dev Tools
- Android Studio
- SCRUM (Trello, Jira)
- Technical documentation

SOFT SKILLS

- Analytical and problem- solving skills.
- Negotiation and communication skills
- Presentation skills; presence and credibility in front of key stakeholders.
- Ability to translate business requirements into technology solutions.
- Receptive to new knowledge, and developed ability to grasp new concepts very quickly

LANGUAGES

• English, German, Ukrainian, Russian

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development CareerFoundry

October 2022 - April 2023

Web Development | SheCodes Responsive SheCodes

August 2022 - September 2022

Web Development | SheCodes Plus SheCodes

July 2022 - August 2022

Introduction to coding | SheCodes Basics SheCodes

June 2022

Master's Degree in International Economy Ukrainian State University of Finance and International Trade

September 2004 - July 2009

WORK HISTORY

General Manager

Cotrestone Group (6.2021-8.2022)

- Recruitment and organization of new departments connected with closing and realization of commercial contracts (sales team, strategic marketing and media planning department, creative and video production team)
- Developing sales strategy and tactics driving business in key market segments and accounts
- Developing and manage key relationships with clients at TOP management organizational level
- Running business negotiations, processing contracts, closing deals with clients and key partners (TV, digital platforms for advertising campaigns)
- Using analysis and econometric modeling to achieve positive ROI for media investments (TV and digital media campaigns)
- Accelerate the growth of revenue for the business and building the customer`s and project`s pipeline

Sales Director B2B

StarLight Media (2.2016-3.2021)

- Analysis of variable Ukrainian market categories, understanding of world markets main features and local customers' characteristics
- Building strong trust relationships with existing and new clients
- Running negotiation process to achieve win-win agreements with clients
- Carrying out a major media investment analysis and preparation of a media strategy for clients (short- and long-term)
- Cooperating with other team members and business units during creation and implementation of media strategies (TV direct advertising, TV sponsorship)
- Cooperation with production and creative teams to achieve high quality brands integration into channel's projects, top TV shows and series of the StarLight Media Group
- Monitoring TV advertising campaigns performance with respect to core KPIs (TRP, GRP, Aff, Reach, CPP, COV) according to Nielsen data and analytics

New Business Manager

TRK Lux (11.2014-1.2016)

- Planning and implementation strategies to attract customers for media services (TV, radio, digital)
- Creation of new GRP pricing strategy for radio advertising campaign using GFK metrics and analytics
- Negotiations with other media holdings to form a single comprehensive offer for advertisers
- Preparing presentations and offers for potential Clients
- Market analyzing and developing the training courses for the sales team to create more competitive offers

Sales Manager

Ukrainian Media Holding (8.2010-10.2014)

- Radio advertising market analysis
- Creating effective media strategies for radio advertising based on GfK and TNS data and analytics
- Assisting with challenging client requests
- Experienced on using CRM software (Zoho CRM)
- Created wide base of regular customers (FMCG, pharmaceutical, gas stations, etc)